Guide to the Beverly Sims Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Beverly Sims papers
1970-1995
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6203
6203-001
Sims, Beverly E.
1.52 cubic feet 4 boxes
The personal papers of Beverly Sims, a Black tradeswoman activist from Seattle, including subject files, correspondence, and writings. Contents of these papers relate to Sims' interests and activist projects, which include work related to the rights of women, third world countries and native peoples.
Sims was born and raised in Seattle. After attending the University of Washington, she worked for Boeing before becoming a secretary at the Northwest Labor and Employment Law Office (now the Legacy of Equality, Leadership, and Organizing).
While at LELO, Sims became involved in Seattle’s radical politics through her friendship with, and later marriage to, Tyree Scott, the leader of the United Construction Workers Association (UCWA). In 1975, Sims entered the apprenticeship program of the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Local 46— the same union that Scott belonged to— through a court-ordered affirmative action plan specifically for black workers. She was the third black woman to ever enter the program, and the first to complete it. She left the trades in the early 1980s following the birth of her son, Seth, and later worked for King County's HIV/ AIDS prevention program.
Source: http://depts.washington.edu/civilr/sims.htm
The collection is arranged into the following series:
SERIES 1: COMMUNICATIONS, 1974-1982
SERIES 2: SUBJECT FILES, 1965-1995
SERIES 3: CASE FILES, 1978-1979
SERIES 4: EPHEMERA AND OTHER FILES, 1965-1985
The personal papers of Beverly Sims consist of subject files, correspondence, writings, notes, and ephemera relating to Sim’s own interests and activist projects, including those related to rights of women, third world countries and native peoples. Of particular interest is the subject file on the NGO Forum on Women held Beijing in 1995; Sims was an attendee of this conference.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
No restrictions on access.
Due to the collection's distinctiveness as a body of records created or acquired during the course of Beverly Sims work and personal life and the importance of bringing out women's contributions to the labor movement whenever possible, this collection was separated from the
Tyree Scott Papers (Collection No. 5245-001)
during processing in 2018.
Tyree Scott photograph collection (Collection No. PH1093)
Sims, Beverly E.$vArchives; African American women$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Labor union members$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Women's rights; Human rights; Labor$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; NGO Forum on Women, Beijing '95$d(1995 :$cHuairou Xian, China); Venceremos Brigade; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal correspondence; Business correspondence; Newsletters; Ephemera; Records (Documents); Poetry; Newspaper clippings; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Women; Civic Activism
- COMMUNICATIONS, 1974-1982; Series 1 (Box-folder 1/1-1/4)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Writings of Others, 1975 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Writings of Others, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/4)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1965-1995; Series 2 (Box-folder 1/5-3/15)
  - Africa (Angola), 1975 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Black Unemployed Workers Organizing Committee, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Campfire House, 1994 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Center for Law and Social Policy, 1979 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Central Area Motivation Program, 1979 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Committee to Save our Hiring Hall, 1981 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Committee to Save our Hiring Hall, 1981 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Cuba, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - International Paper, 1976 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Latin America, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Middle East, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Mitos, 1976 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Native Americans, 1975 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Native Americans, 1976 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - NGO Forum on Women, Beijing (1 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - NGO Forum on Women, Beijing (2 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - NGO Forum on Women, 1995 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - NGO Forum on Women (1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - NGO Forum on Women (2 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - International Women's Rights, NGO Forum on Women, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - NGO Forum on Women, 1995 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - NGO Forum on Women, Chinese Currency and Bus Passes, circa 1980s (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Notary Public, 1978 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Puerto Rico, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Rape Relief, circa 1970s (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Resources for Community Change, 1976 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Seattle Liberation Coalition, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Study Group, 1976 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Venceremos Brigade Publication, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1975 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Venceremos Applications, 1976 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Venceremos Brigade, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Venceremos Brigade (1 of 2), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Venceremos Brigade (2 of 2), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Women's Struggles, 1975 (Box-folder 3/15)
- CASE FILES, 1978-1979; Series 3 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Advocates for Women vs. Marshall, Department of Labor, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 3/16)
- EPHEMERA AND OTHER FILES, 1965-1985; Series 4 (Box-folder 3/17-4/5)
  - Notes, 1975, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Lists, circa 1970s (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Leaflets, Fliers and Handouts, 1982 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Forms, 1982 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Songs, circa 1970s (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Poetry, 1979 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Ephemera, 1975 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Clippings, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 4/5)